A Guide to the Confederate Pension Records, 1884-1978
Library of Virginia
- Series V: Correspondence, 1921-1977., Extent: 32 boxes. (Box 78-102.)
  - Subseries B: Deceased Daughters, 1965-1977., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 89-91.)
    The Deceased Daughters subseries is housed in three archival boxes and is arranged in chronological order, then alphabetically by pensioner. This series contains the agency copy of the Department of Treasury form No. 58 from the treasurer to Maxie Duty or Nancy W. Stoll, Confederate Pension Administrator, concerning returned pension checks for deceased daughters of Confederate veterans. These forms provide the name & address of the pensioner, date dropped from the pension roll, roll number, date deceased, and explanation for return (e.g. unknown, moved, deceased). Also includes correspondence from Maxie Duty to individuals, usually relatives, regarding the death of a pensioner. The subseries sometimes includes notice of death cards submitted for deceased daughters, death certificates (restricted for fifty years), obituaries, and memorial cards.
    - 1965-1966
      - A-K (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - L-Y (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - 1967-1968
      - A-G (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - H-P (Box 89, Folder 4)
      - R-Z (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - 1969-1970
      - A-G (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - H-Y (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - 1970-1971
      - A-L (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - M-W (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - 1971-1972
      - A-H (Box 90, Folder 5)
      - I-Q (Box 90, Folder 6)
      - R-W (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - 1973-1974
      - A-G (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - H-P (Box 91, Folder 2)
      - R-W (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - 1974-1975
      - B-M (Box 91, Folder 4)
      - N-Y (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Subseries C: Deceased Widows, 1960-1973., Extent: 1 box. (Box 92.)
    The Deceased Widows subseries is housed in one archival box and is arranged in chronological order, then alphabetically by pensioner. This subseries contains correspondence from Maxie Duty or Nancy W. Stoll, Confederate Pension Administrator, regarding the deaths of Confederate widows and their funeral allowance. These records often include the form No. 58 mentioned in the Deceased Daughters subseries, notice of death cards, invoices for funeral allowance, and death certificates.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1960-1962 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - 1970-1973 (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Subseries D: Incoming Correspondence, 1923-1925., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 93-94.)
    The Incoming Correspondence subseries is housed in two archival boxes and is arranged alphabetically by veteran or pensioner. This subseries differs from the Pension Clerk's Correspondence subseries in that it does not include the outgoing response of the Pension Clerk. This subseries contains change of address/death of pensioner notification cards sent to the Auditor of Public Accounts. These cards have been arranged to the rear of each folder. The correspondence was sent to John H. Johnson, Pension Clerk, & C. Lee Moore, Auditor of Public Accounts, and relates to requests for pension applications - especially from county clerks, returned checks for deceased veterans & widows, and notification of deaths of pensioners.
    - A (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - B (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - C (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - D (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - E (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - F (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - G (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - H (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - I (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - J (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - K (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - L (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - M (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - N (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - O (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - P (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - R (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - S (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - T (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - U (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - V (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - W (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - Y (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - Subseries E: Pension Clerk's Correspondence, 1921-1925., Extent: 14 boxes. (Box 95-102a.)
    The Pension Clerk's Correspondence subseries is housed in fourteen archival boxes and is arranged alphabetically by correspondent or pensioner. This subseries documents correspondence sent to and from John H. Johnson as pension clerk. The correspondence relates to pensions for Confederate veterans & widows, the war records of veterans, payments of claims, funeral expense claims, deaths of pensioners, the rerating of pensions in cases of total disability, searches for Civil War pensioners among the Confederate war records at the Virginia State Library, and the receipt of pension payments or missing payments. The correspondence often includes change of address or death of pensioner cards submitted by pensioners or their next of kin to C. Lee Moore, Auditor of Public Accounts. Noteworthy is a letter from John Saunders, Attorney General, to the pension clerk regarding his opinion respecting the eligibility of West Virginia residents who entered the Lee Camp Home in Virginia.
    Several files from 1925 were discovered after processing was completed. Though not individually processed they were filed at the end of each alphabetic letter.
    - 1921 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - 1922-1925
      - Aaron-Agnew (Box 95, Folder 2)
      - Albert-Applewhite (Box 95, Folder 3)
      - Archer-Ayres (Box 95, Folder 4)
      - Baach-Bayne (Box 95, Folder 5)
      - Beahm-Bly (Box 95, Folder 6)
      - Board-Boykin (Box 96, Folder 1)
      - Bracy-Brough (Box 96, Folder 2)
      - Brown-Burchett (Box 96, Folder 3)
      - Burfoot-Bywaters (Box 96, Folder 4)
      - Cabbell-Carroll (Box 96, Folder 5)
      - Carter-Chewning (Box 96a, Folder 1)
      - Clark-Clapsaddle (Box 96a, Folder 2)
      - Coakley-Cox (Box 96a, Folder 3)
      - Crabtree-Catherell (Box 96a, Folder 4)
      - C (Box 96a, Folder 5)
      - Dabney-Day (Box 96b, Folder 1)
      - Dean-Downing (Box 96b, Folder 2)
      - Drew-Dyer (Box 96b, Folder 3)
      - D (Box 96b, Folder 4)
      - Earle-Eversole (Box 96b, Folder 5)
      - E (Box 96b, Folder 6)
      - Fahnestock-Flowers (Box 97, Folder 1)
      - Foley-Fussell (Box 97, Folder 2)
      - F (Box 97, Folder 3)
      - Gallasher-Gouldman (Box 97, Folder 4)
      - Grady-Guynn (Box 97, Folder 5)
      - Hackley-Harrell (Box 97a, Folder 1)
      - Harris-Hazleton (Box 97a, Folder 2)
      - Head-Howie (Box 97a, Folder 3)
      - Hubbard-Hypes (Box 97a, Folder 4)
      - H (Box 97a, Folder 5)
      - Kagey-Kuhn (Box 98, Folder 1)
      - K (Box 98, Folder 2)
      - Laffoon-Lewis (Box 98, Folder 3)
      - Lindamood-Lytton (Box 98, Folder 4)
      - L (Box 98, Folder 5)
      - Mackall-Mays (Box 98, Folder 6)
      - McAlister-McNew (Box 98a, Folder 1)
      - Meade-Mize (Box 98a, Folder 2)
      - Modena-Myers (Box 98a, Folder 3)
      - M (Box 98a, Folder 4-5)
      - M (Box 99, Folder 1)
      - N (Box 99, Folder 2-3)
      - O (Box 99, Folder 4-5)
      - Pace-Petty (Box 99, Folder 6)
      - Phelps-Putnam (Box 99, Folder 7)
      - P (Box 100, Folder 1)
      - Q (Box 100, Folder 2)
      - Ragland-Rhodes (Box 100, Folder 3)
      - Roadcap-Rutherford (Box 100, Folder 4)
      - R (Box 100, Folder 5)
      - Sadler-Seward (Box 101, Folder 1)
      - Shaffer-Slayton (Box 101, Folder 2)
      - Small-Smythe (Box 101, Folder 3)
      - Snavely-Strickler (Box 101, Folder 4)
      - Stewart-Synn (Box 101, Folder 5)
      - S (Box 101, Folder 6)
      - S (Box 101a, Folder 1)
      - Tabb-Teets (Box 101a, Folder 2)
      - Thacker-Thurston (Box 101a, Folder 3)
      - Tignor-Tyree (Box 101a, Folder 4)
      - T (Box 101a, Folder 5)
      - U (Box 101a, Folder 6)
      - V (Box 102, Folder 1)
      - Wade-Westmoreland (Box 102, Folder 2)
      - Wharton-Wily (Box 102, Folder 3)
      - Winder-Wysor (Box 102, Folder 4)
      - W (Box 102, Folder 5)
      - W (Box 102a, Folder 1)
      - Y (Box 102a, Folder 2)
      - Z (Box 102a, Folder 3)
- Series VI: Funeral Expenses, 1926-1967., Extent: 13 boxes. (Box 103-115.)
  The Funeral Expenses series is housed in thirteen archival boxes and is arranged in two series. Series have been designated for Allowed and Disallowed funeral expenses. This series documents claims for funeral expenses submitted by the administrators or executors of Civil War veterans and widows according to the act of the General Assembly of 1908. The bulk of the material can be found in the Allowed funeral expenses subseries.
  Arranged in two series.
  - Subseries A: Allowed Claims, 1926-1967., Extent: 12 boxes.
    The Allowed Funeral Expenses subseries is housed in eleven archival boxes and is arranged in chronological order, then alphabetical by locality with cities in the rear. This series contains lists of funeral expense claims. The earliest claims, between 1926 & 1929, provide the name of the administrator & the estate, along with the amount of the claim by the Chief Pension Clerk. The claims also include invoices sent to the Comptroller documenting the payment of funeral expenses for widows, as well as certified copies of death records. In addition, there is often correspondence from Maxie Duty, Confederate Pension Administrator, to funeral homes, undertakers, and other individuals regarding funeral expenses for Civil War veterans & widows. Occasionally, the files contain pension cards for the widows receiving funeral expenses. The later funeral expense claims, 1945 to 1967, are arranged chronologically, then alphabetically by locality with cities arranged to the rear. These claims provide the name of the administrator, administratrix, executor or executrix, name of deceased pensioner, nature of expense, amount of funeral expense, and clerk of the circuit court's certificate. These claims also include an excerpt from the funeral expense law which grants twenty-five dollars after proof of death and claim is certified for any Confederate pensioner on the pension roll of Virginia. The claims include correspondence to & from executor to the Auditor, John H. Johnson as Pension Clerk, and others regarding claims for funeral expenses. Lastly, the claims often include copies of death certificates and accounts of funeral directors & undertakers.
    Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically by locality.
    - 1926-1929 (Box 103, Folder 1)
      - Accomack (Box 103, Folder 1)
      - Albemarle (Box 103, Folder 2)
      - Alleghany (Box 103, Folder 3)
      - Amelia (Box 103, Folder 4)
      - Amherst (Box 103, Folder 5)
      - Appomattox (Box 103, Folder 6)
      - Arlington (Box 103, Folder 7)
      - Augusta (Box 103, Folder 8)
      - Bath (Box 103, Folder 9)
      - Bedford (Box 103, Folder 10)
      - Bland (Box 103, Folder 11)
      - Botetourt (Box 104, Folder 1)
      - Brunswick (Box 104, Folder 2)
      - Buchanan (Box 104, Folder 3)
      - Buckingham (Box 104, Folder 4)
      - Campbell (Box 104, Folder 5)
      - Caroline (Box 104, Folder 6)
      - Carroll (Box 104, Folder 7)
      - Charlotte (Box 104, Folder 8)
      - Chesterfield (Box 104, Folder 9)
      - Clarke (Box 104, Folder 10)
      - Craig (Box 104, Folder 11)
      - Culpeper (Box 104, Folder 12)
      - Cumberland (Box 104, Folder 13)
      - Dickenson (Box 105, Folder 1)
      - Dinwiddie (Box 105, Folder 2)
      - Elizabeth City (Box 105, Folder 3)
      - Essex (Box 105, Folder 4)
      - Fairfax (Box 105, Folder 5)
      - Fauquier (Box 105, Folder 6)
      - Floyd (Box 105, Folder 7)
      - Fluvanna (Box 105, Folder 8)
      - Franklin (Box 105, Folder 9)
      - Frederick (Box 105, Folder 10)
      - Giles (Box 105, Folder 11)
      - Gloucester (Box 105, Folder 12)
      - Goochland (Box 105, Folder 13)
      - Grayson (Box 105, Folder 14)
      - Greene (Box 106, Folder 1)
      - Greensville (Box 106, Folder 2)
      - Halifax (Box 106, Folder 3)
      - Hanover (Box 106, Folder 4)
      - Henrico (Box 106, Folder 5)
      - Henry (Box 106, Folder 6)
      - Highland (Box 106, Folder 7)
      - Isle of Wight (Box 106, Folder 8)
      - James City (Box 106, Folder 9)
      - King & Queen (Box 106, Folder 10)
      - King George (Box 106, Folder 11)
      - King William (Box 106, Folder 12)
      - Lancaster (Box 106, Folder 13)
      - Lee (Box 106, Folder 14)
      - Loudoun (Box 106, Folder 15)
      - Louisa (Box 106, Folder 16)
      - Lunenburg (Box 106, Folder 17)
      - Madison (Box 106, Folder 18)
      - Mathews (Box 107, Folder 1)
      - Mecklenburg (Box 107, Folder 2)
      - Middlesex (Box 107, Folder 3)
      - Montgomery (Box 107, Folder 4)
      - Nansemond (Box 107, Folder 5)
      - Nelson (Box 107, Folder 6)
      - New Kent (Box 107, Folder 7)
      - Norfolk (Box 107, Folder 8)
      - Northampton (Box 107, Folder 9)
      - Northumberland (Box 107, Folder 10)
      - Nottoway (Box 107, Folder 11)
      - Orange (Box 107, Folder 12)
      - Page (Box 107, Folder 13)
      - Patrick (Box 107, Folder 14)
      - Pittsylvania (Box 107, Folder 15)
      - Powhatan (Box 108, Folder 1)
      - Prince Edward (Box 108, Folder 2)
      - Prince George (Box 108, Folder 3)
      - Prince William (Box 108, Folder 4)
      - Pulaski (Box 108, Folder 5)
      - Rappahannock (Box 108, Folder 6)
      - Richmond (Box 108, Folder 7)
      - Roanoke (Box 108, Folder 8)
      - Rockbridge (Box 108, Folder 9)
      - Rockingham (Box 108, Folder 10)
      - Russell (Box 108, Folder 11)
      - Scott (Box 108, Folder 12)
      - Shenandoah (Box 108, Folder 13)
      - Smyth (Box 109, Folder 1)
      - Southampton (Box 109, Folder 2)
      - Spotsylvania (Box 109, Folder 3)
      - Stafford (Box 109, Folder 4)
      - Surry (Box 109, Folder 5)
      - Sussex (Box 109, Folder 6)
      - Tazewell (Box 109, Folder 7)
      - Warren (Box 109, Folder 8)
      - Warwick (Box 109, Folder 9)
      - Washington (Box 109, Folder 10)
      - Westmoreland (Box 109, Folder 11)
      - Wise (Box 109, Folder 12)
      - Wythe (Box 109, Folder 13)
      - York (Box 109, Folder 14)
      - Alexandria (Box 110, Folder 1)
      - Bristol (Box 110, Folder 2)
      - Buena Vista (Box 110, Folder 3)
      - Charlottesville (Box 110, Folder 4)
      - Clifton Forge (Box 110, Folder 5)
      - Danville (Box 110, Folder 6)
      - Fredericksburg (Box 110, Folder 7)
      - Hopewell (Box 110, Folder 8)
      - Lynchburg (Box 110, Folder 9)
      - Newport News (Box 110, Folder 10)
      - Norfolk (Box 110, Folder 11)
      - Petersburg (Box 110, Folder 12)
      - Portsmouth (Box 110, Folder 13)
      - Radford (Box 110, Folder 14)
      - Richmond
        - 1926-1927 (Box 110, Folder 15)
        - 1927-1929 (Box 110, Folder 16)
      - Roanoke
        - 1926-1927 (Box 111, Folder 1)
        - 1928-1929 (Box 111, Folder 2)
      - Staunton (Box 111, Folder 3)
      - Williamsburg (Box 111, Folder 4)
      - Winchester (Box 111, Folder 5)
      - Washington, D.C. (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - 1945 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - 1949
      - Counties (Box 111, Folder 8)
      - Cities (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - 1950
      - Counties
        - Appomattox-Madison (Box 111, Folder 10)
        - Middlesex-Wythe (Box 111, Folder 11)
      - Cities (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - 1951 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - 1952
      - Counties (Box 112, Folder 2)
      - Cities (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - 1953
      - Counties (Box 112, Folder 4)
      - Cities (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - 1954
      - Counties (Box 112, Folder 6)
      - Cities (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - 1955 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - 1956 (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - 1957 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - 1958 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - 1959 (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - 1960 (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 113, Folder 8)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 113, Folder 9)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 114, Folder 2)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Subseries B: Disallowed Claims, 1908-1929., Extent: 1 box.
    The Disallowed Funeral Expenses subseries is housed in one archival box and is arranged alphabetically by locality. This subseries includes funeral expense accounts, correspondence, and death certificates. The correspondence consists of mostly outgoing letters from John H. Johnson as Pension Clerk to the administrator or executor of the veteran's estate regarding the reasons for the disallowed claim. These funeral expense claims were disallowed because the claim was already paid, the claimant does not appear on the pension roll, the pensioner was in an asylum or Solder's Home, or the pensioner died before they were enrolled.
    Arranged alphabetically by locality.
    - Albemarle-Essex (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Fairfax-Lunenburg (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Madison-Russell (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Scott-Wythe (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Danville-Staunton & Alabama (Box 115, Folder 5)
- Series VII: Miscellaneous, 1884-1973., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 116-118.)
  The Miscellaneous series is housed in three archival boxes and is arranged in alphabetical order. This series contains court orders, disbursements, legislation, ledgers, powers of attorney, treasurer's reports, and other sundry items. The Court Orders were submitted by various cities & counties and are arranged alphabetically by locality. These orders relate to the approval of rerating applications between 1917 & 1925. The orders provide the names of the pension applicant and sometimes the veteran's unit. The orders also include letters from county clerks to the auditor, C. Lee Moore. The Powers of Attorney concern to the appointment of individuals to serve as committee for pensioners, appointments to pension boards, and certificates of qualification. The Treasurer's Reports were created by the Auditor of Public Accounts between 1913 & 1925 on account of the death of pensioners. These reports include the date, check number, county, payee, & amount. Also noteworthy is a file devoted to John Salling who was supposedly the last surviving Confederate veteran from Virginia who died in 1959 at the age of 112. This file includes Salling's application for a pension in 1950. Lastly, there is a chronological list of disbursements of the appropriations for disabled soldiers which provides the name of the veteran, date of disbursement, residence, & amount of disbursement between 1884 & 1887.
  - Change of Address/Deaths, 1959-1960. (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Court Orders, 1917-1925.
    - Albemarle-Cumberland (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Danville-Greene (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Halifax-Newport News (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Norfolk-Petersburg (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Pittsylvania-Richmond (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - Roanoke-York (Box 116, Folder 7)
  - Disbursements of the Appropriations for Disabled Soldiers, 1884-1887. (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Federal Pension Law, 1958-1967. (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Home for Needy Confederate Women, 1966. (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - Pension Instructions, 1955-1961. (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Pension Laws, 1934-1973. (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Pension List, 1888-1908. (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Pension Payroll Ledger, circa 1890.
    - Accomack-Fluvanna (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Franklin-Nelson (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - New Kent-Southampton (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - Spotsylvania-Washington, D.C. (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Pension Roll Sheets (Widow), 1960. (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - Powers of Attorney/Certificates of Qualification, 1933-1964. (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Salling, John (Last Confederate Veteran), 1950-1972. (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1913-1927. (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Oversized
    - Applications - Rerating Applications - Allowed - Campbell County, 1905-1909 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Applications - Rerating Applications - Allowed - Caroline County, 1906-1908 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - Deceased Widows - 1961-1962 - Pension Roll Sheet (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous - Pension Roll Sheet (Widow), 1960 (Box 119, Folder 4)
- Series VIII: Volumes, 1924-1978., Extent: 35 volumes. (Volume 1-35.)
  The Volumes series consists of thirty-five volumes and is arranged in four subseries. Subseries have been designated for Daughter Pensions, Veteran & Widow Pensions, Registers, and Warrant Registers. These volumes document the payment of pensions to Confederate veterans and the widows and daughters of veterans.
  Arranged in four subseries.
  - Subseries A: Pensions - Daughters, 1924-1954., Extent: 7 volumes.
    The Daughter Pensions subseries consists of seven volumes and is arranged chronologically, then by warrant number. These volumes were maintained by the State Comptroller and serve as pension warrant registers. The volumes include a number, name, warrant number, and amount paid. The volumes from 1924 to 1938 include the name, address, and quarterly pension payments. These earlier volumes are arranged chronologically, then alphabetically by pensioner.
    - 1924 July-1930 July (Volume 1)
    - 1928 April-1937 July (Volume 2)
    - 1931 July-1938 July (Volume 3)
    - 1937 October-1942 April (Volume 4)
    - 1939 July-1948 July (Volume 5)
    - 1948 July-1953 December (Volume 6)
    - 1954 January-1958 November (Volume 7)
  - Subseries B: Pensions - Veterans & Widows, 1933-1958., Extent: 24 volumes.
    The Veteran and Widow Pensions subseries consists of twenty-four volumes and is arranged chronologically, then by warrant number. These volumes were maintained by the State Comptroller and serve as pension warrant registers. The volumes include a number, name, warrant number, and amount paid. These volumes also include accounts of pension & funeral expenses paid and summaries of pensions paid to veterans, widows, and servants. The earlier volumes also include the address of the pensioner.
    - 1933 January-April (Volume 8)
    - 1933 May-August (Volume 9)
    - 1933 September-December (Volume 10)
    - 1934 January-April (Volume 11)
    - 1934 May-September (Volume 12)
    - 1934 September-1935 January (Volume 13)
    - 1935 January-July (Volume 14)
    - 1935 July-1936 January (Volume 15)
    - 1936 January-July (Volume 16)
    - 1936 July-1937 January (Volume 17)
    - 1937 January-July (Volume 18)
    - 1937 July-December (Volume 19)
    - 1938 January-July (Volume 20)
    - 1938 July-1939 January (Volume 21)
    - 1939 January-July (incl. Funeral Expenses, 1939-1941) (Volume 22)
    - 1939 July-1940 July (Volume 23)
    - 1940 July-1941 July (Volume 24)
    - 1941 July-1942 July (Volume 25)
    - 1942 July-1943 July (Volume 26)
    - 1943 July-1945 July (Volume 27)
    - 1945 July-1948 July (Volume 28)
    - 1948 July-1951 January (Volume 29)
    - 1951 January-1954 July (Volume 30)
    - 1954 July- 1958 December (Volume 31)
  - Subseries C: Registers, 1933-1947., Extent: 1 volume.
    The Registers subseries consists of one volume and is arranged alphabetically by pensioner. This volume includes the name, locality, date received, disposition (approved or disallowed), amount of pension by class (A-F), date, and remarks (e.g. Act of 1932, pensioner's age, date enrolled, date married, etc.).
    Arranged alphabetically by pensioner.
    - 1933-1947 (Volume 32)
  - Subseries D: Warrant Registers, 1961-1978., Extent: 3 volumes.
    The Warrant Registers subseries consists of three volumes and is arranged chronologically, then by warrant number. These volumes include the name of the payee, agency code, account number, book number, warrant number, and amount paid.
    - 1961 January-1964 June (Volume 33)
    - 1964 July-1971 June (Volume 34)
    - 1971 July-1978 June (Volume 35)